Theodore R. Cogswell Papers
Theodore R. Cogswell Papers
- Writings
  - Book reviews
    - Spender, Stephen / Poems of Dedication, 1947; clipping of published version only (Box 10)
    - multiple (Minneapolis Tribune columns), 1971-1972; clippings of published columns (Box 10)
  - Essays
    - Authorship of the Scottish Troy fragments, mix of typed and handwritten notes, drafts, tabulations (Box 11)
    - Notes on the artist and society, typescript carbon, minor revisions (Box 11)
    - Soviet bloc science fiction, typescript carbons (Box 11)
  - Juvenilia
    - Miscellaneous, typescript, typescript carbons, some with revisions (Box 11)
  - Plays and scripts
    - The Boomerang, "a story idea for television"; typescript of treatment only, no script (Box 11)
    - Cassandra and the unicorn, typescripts, typescript carbons, some with revisions (Box 11)
    - Contact point, typescript, first two pages missing (Box 11)
    - Double indemnity / Third time down, very rough/incomplete typed notes, drafts with numerous revisions (Box 11)
    - If garages operated the way hospitals do, handwritten draft, incomplete (Box 11)
    - The King of the schnorers, very rough/incomplete draft with extensive corrections and annotations (Box 11)
    - Operation Tel Aviv, typescript, typescript carbon, photocopy of published version (Box 11)
    - The Question, mimeographed copy of typescript (Box 11)
    - Rocky King, Detective: Murder on the Midway (with Larry Sloan), typescript carbons (Box 11)
    - The Short count, typescript, typescript carbon, minor revisions; see also Stories: Short count (Box 11)
    - Space slugs, typescript with corrections (Box 11)
    - The UHF murder case (with Alan Shirey), treatment only, typescript carbon (Box 11)
    - The W. S. murder case, very rough/incomplete handwritten draft, summary (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 11)
  - Poems
    - Faex delenda est, multiple drafts, published version in Maledicta, correspondence with editor Reinhold Aman (Box 11)
    - Pilgrim's progress, multiple drafts with different titles; folder also includes drafts of a few other poems (Box 11)
    - Placebos for the orthodox (collection), title pages for sections, final self-published(?) version inscribed to George (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous titled, A-Z, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous untitled and fragments (Box 11)
  - Songs
    - The Friggin' falcon, lyrics only; typescript, copies of published version (Box 15)
    - Korean blues, music only (Box 15)
    - The Roper, lyrics, music, letter to a Mr. Niles about the song (Box 15)
    - Soft and deadly people, lyrics, music (Box 15)
    - The Song of the fighting QMs, lyrics only (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous, fragments and unidentified (Box 15)
  - Stories
    - A is for analog, mix of handwritten and typescript drafts, notes, etc. (Box 12)
    - Anniversary present (alternate title: Private line), typescript, typescript carbons (Box 12)
    - The Big stink (alternate title: Gentlemen's agreement), typescript, typescript carbon, clipping of published version (Box 12)
    - The Burning, typescript carbon of story, typescript carbon of introduction to story (Box 12)
    - Cabbage patch (earlier title: Bedtime story), typescript, typescript carbons (Box 12)
    - Case history, typescripts, typescript carbons, some with revisions (Box 12)
    - Consumer report (alternate title: No gun to the victor), typescript carbons; clipping of published version (Box 12)
    - Daybreak, handwritten draft (Box 12)
    - Disassembly line (alternate title: The nose), typescript, typescript carbons (Box 12)
    - Early bird, photocopy of typescript, with revisions (Box 12)
    - Emergency rations, typescript carbon, minor revisions (Box 12)
    - The falling man, typescripts, typescript carbons, some with revisions (Box 12)
    - Garth of the golden hand, novel outline, photocopy of typescript, some revisions; folder also contains some pages with characters "Wolf" and "Kurtos" which may be from a different story (Box 12)
    - The golden people, typescript, typescript carbon, both with revisions (Box 12)
    - Grandfather clause, typescript with revisions and handwritten added pages, typescript carbon (Box 12)
    - The Hamlet murder case (alternate title: The adventure of the murdered king), mix of typed and handwritten notes, synopses (Box 12)
    - Invasion report (alternate title: Delinquency report), two typescript carbons, one about 50% longer than the other (Box 12)
    - Journeys with three Margarets, typescript carbons, multiple drafts (Box 12)
    - Kevin and the goblins, novel; mix of typescript and handwritten drafts, notes (Box 13)
    - Limiting factor, typescript, typescript carbon (Box 13)
    - Local trouble (alternate title: Alan and the WOCs), novel; typescripts, multiple drafts, numerous revisions and edits (Box 13)
    - Lover boy, typescript carbon (Box 13)
    - Machine record (alternate title: Mousetrap), with Walter Tevis, typescript drafts (Box 13)
    - The man who knew Grodnick (alternate title: Reggie), typescript, typescript carbons with revisions (Box 13)
    - The masters, typescript carbon (Box 13)
    - Minimum sentence (alternate title: Love story), typescript (Box 13)
    - Mr. Hoskin's heel, typescript, typescript carbons, both with revisions; clipping of published piece (Box 13)
    - The misplaced weapon, typescript with corrections; typed on back of some other piece (Box 13)
    - Natural enemy, numerous drafts with revisions, typescript and typescript carbons (Box 13)
    - Neutral corner, novel; typescript with revisions (Box 13)
      See also Correspondence: Davenport, Basil.
    - Oedipus wrecked, typescript (Box 14)
    - The other cheek, typescript, typescript carbon with revisions (Box 14)
    - Pain reaction (with Hal D. Randolph), typescript carbon (Box 14)
    - Paradise regained, typescript carbon (Box 14)
    - The patsy, typescript with revisions, appears to be incomplete (Box 14)
    - Players at null-G (with Algis Budrys, Ted Thomas), typescript with extensive revisions; includes correspondence from Ted Thomas regarding the story (Box 14)
    - The prangler, typescript with revisions (Box 14)
    - Prisoner of love, typescript carbon, minor revisions (Box 14)
    - Shell game, typescript carbon with revisions; typed on the back of some other piece(s) (Box 14)
    - The short count, multiple drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, minor corrections; see also Plays/scripts: Short count (Box 14)
    - The specter general, novella; typescript carbon and summary of "expansion" to story (Box 14)
    - Spock, Messiah, drafts, notes; mix of handwritten and typed (Box 15)
    - Spock, Messiah, galleys (Box 15)
    - Spock, Messiah, typescript photocopy with revisions (Box 15)
    - A spudget for Thwilbert (alternate title: The warlord of Hun), typescript and carbons, at least two drafts (Box 14)
    - Test area, typescript carbon, minor revisions (Box 14)
    - Things, typescript carbon with revisions (Box 14)
    - Thrud (with Hal Randolph), several drafts with revisions, one noting the author as "Randolph Cogswell"; includes rejection letter from Asimov Science Fiction Magazine (Box 14)
    - Training device, typescript (Box 14)
    - The wall around the world, typescript carbon (Box 14)
    - The war that had to be lost, handwritten notes only (Box 14)
    - Wolfie, typescript carbon (Box 14)
    - You know Willie (alternate title: Judgement night), typescript carbons (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Cogswell's multiple Marys (Box 16)
    - Editing the Nebula Award anthology (Box 16)
    - Factoryville Junior College… [humorous press release] (Box 16)
    - Fragments (Box 16)
    - Front matter, unidentified (Box 16)
    - Lecture materials (Box 16)
    - Lineage [Malcolm II, King of Scotland] (Box 16)
    - Science Fiction Associates [synopses, mimeograph copy] (Box 16)
    - Story ideas (Box 16)
    - Tan calculations (Box 16)
    - [Teen anthology ideas], correspondence with various authors regarding suggestions, feasibility, etc. (Box 16)
    - The third eye (a preface to a novel that will never be written) (Box 16)
    - Works in progress (Box 16)
    - Writing Arts program proposal (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous by others
    - Aldiss, Ellison, Van Vogt, story, The players of null wave (Box 16)
    - Anderson, Poul, poems, part of a script (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 16)